<buffaloSoldiers>
  <quizContext>
    <fullName>Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club History - Test Your Knowledge</fullName>
    <shortName>Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club Quiz</shortName>
    <description>This Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club Quiz has been designed to both inform and to test your knowledge of the history of the Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club.  The quiz touches on
      the originally founding to the current day highlighting some points during it's formation, mission and accomplishments.  Any references to club statistics, like number of chapters etc, are
      correct at the time of the writing but of course may change.
    </description>
    <powellDedication>
    </powellDedication>
    <version>1.0</version>
  </quizContext>

  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Formation">
    <question>
      The Buffalo Soliders motorcycle club was initially established by Kenneth 'Dream Maker' Thomas in Chicago in October 1993 after he left the "Buffalo Soldier Motorcycle Club".
      He formed a new motorcycle club and initially named it:
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club of Chicago
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Buffalo Troopers Motorcycle Club of Chicago
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      National Association of Buffalo Soldiers and Troopers Motorcycle Club
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is a. &lt;br&gt;After the initial formation of the club the name was changed to the
      "Buffalo Troopers Motorcycle Club of Chicago" in order to avoid confustion with the previously existing club.  Then in 1999
      the "National Association of Buffalo Soldiers and Troopers Motorcycle Club" was formed with the Chicago chapter identified as the mother chapter.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Formation">
    <question>
      In August of 1994, Brian Bulow of Maryland met Dream Maker, President of what was then called the "Buffalo Troopers of Chicago" and formed a new chapter with
      the name "Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club of Southern Maryland" thus becoming the first chapter to use the name “Buffalo Soldiers”.   Since that start there are now
      120 Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club chapters in 34 states.  California has the most chapters with nine.  Two states have eight chapters each.  They are:
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      Virginia and Alabama
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Virginia and Florida
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Texas and Florida
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Virginia and Georgia
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Alabama and Florida
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is b.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Organization">
    <question>
      While the Buffalo Soliders Motorcycle Club was initially established in Chicago it quickly grew.  Today chapters across the country
      are organized into five regions called Frontiers.  Which of these is not a Frontier:
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      Northeast Frontier
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Southeast Frontier
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Great Lakes Frontier
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Pacific Coast Frontier
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Central Frontier
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is d. &lt;br&gt;Chapters in the western portion of the US belong to the "Western Frontier"
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Organization">
    <question>
      As mentioned the Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club operates with a purpose and mission.  A set of
      operating guidelines guide both national and chapter operations and policy - the IRS Compliance Bu Laws.
      As the name suggests that bylaws are in place also to support the clubs charter as a Nonprofit ​Public ​Benefit ​Corporation
      with IRS code 501(c)(3) designation.  In addtion the bylaws address the following except one, which is it:
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      The organization of the club, selection of officers, and running meetings.
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Chapter and member policy including rules for resolving conflicts and points of appeal
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Selection of officers and the roles of the executive board and national council
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Guidelines for community service and charitable giving
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Fiscal reporting
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      All are correct
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is d.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Mission">
    <question>
      The Southeast Frontier is comprised of 30 Chapters located across five states - Alabama, Florida, Georgia and North and South Carolina.
      The Southeast Frontier is united in the belief that geographic distance will not stand in the way of great successes founded on
      shared philosophy, history, and eagerness to serve in our communitites.  To support this the Frontier has defined seven core values. Four are
      Transparency, Professionalism, Results Orientation, and Member Focus.  Which are the other three:
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      Collaboration, Egotism, and Accountability
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Participation, Accountability, Individualism
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Participation, Individualism, and Collaboration
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Collaboration, Participation, and Accountability
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is d. &lt;br&gt;Egotism and Individualism are not traits consistent with the club's emphasis
      on brotherhood, fellowship, and community.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Mission">
    <question>
      The Buffalo Soliders Motorcycle Club's mission is described in multiple ways. It is represented in mesasging from the national organization, in communication from the national president, and in our creed.
      Which is not a described mission of the Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club?
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      Educate, serve, and ride
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Educate the general public on the history of the 9th and 10th Calvary
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Join the struggle to promote racial equality by egaging politically to support those with a progressive agenda.
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Demonstrate respect
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      None.  All represent stated goals of the Buffalo Soldiers Motorcycle Club.
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is c. &lt;br&gt;As a non-peofit organization it is "prohibited from directly or indirectly
      participating in, or intervening in, any political campaign on behalf of (or in opposition to) any candidate for elective public office".
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Mission">
    <question>
      The Northeast Frontier summarizes the mission of the Buffalo Soldiers - Our objective is to educate those that are unfamiliar with the racism,
      sacrifices and hardships that the Buffalo Soldiers of the 9th and 10th U.S. Cavalries had to
      endure. Our vision is to instill this knowledge into the minds and hearts of our youth of today
      so that we can motivate them to become better citizens and leaders of tomorrow.
      Which of these is not a descsribed focus area within those objectives:
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      Promote good citizenship, establish love and fellowship among all citizens
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Promote motorcycle riding safety
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Promote an ego centric behavior when riding
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Be role models to our community
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is c.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Accomplishments">
    <question>
      In additonal to community service the Buffalo Soldiers help promote educational opportunities by awarding
      Scholarships to students entering college.  This is a competitive selection with opportunities provided at
      national, frontier, and chapter levels.  Which is true
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      The specification of scholarships and the criteria for selection are defined at the National level in the bylaws.
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      Chapters and Frontiers can determine their own scholarship application process and the criteria for selection
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      National requires Chapters to award yearly scholarships or risk sanctions potentially leading to probation
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      IRS 501(c)(3) rules prohibit minority status from being used as a selection criteria in the awarding of scholarships
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is b.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Accomplishments">
    <question>
      Giving back to the community is a cornerstone of the Buffalo Soldiers.  These are community
      projects organized by caring individuals at the chapter level.  Here is just a sampling of the
      community outreach.  But which is not a community project of the Buffalo Soldiers:
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      In the &lt;b&gt;Northeast Frontier&lt;/b&gt; the Hampton Roads, VA chapter maintains active community outreach
      having particiapted in many programs supporting local schools, nursing homes, hospitals and others.  They
      sponsored the dedication of a flag pole at the Cuffeytown Historic Cemetery which interrs
      the largest number of African American Union Civil War soldiers in any non-governmental and non-veteran organization cemetery in Virginia
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      In the &lt;b&gt;Southeast Frontier&lt;/b&gt; the Raleigh, NC chapter is in a year-long effort to provide resources and manpower to
      help revitalize a cemetery dating back to the post civil war and largely providing place of burial
      for African-Americans.
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      In the &lt;b&gt;Great Lakes Frontier&lt;/b&gt; the Michigan chapter worked hard on community service during the pandemic.
      In 2020 chapter members volunteered over 160 hrs of combined community service ranging from food distribution to helping
      with the Flint water crisis.
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      In the &lt;b&gt;Central Frontier&lt;/b&gt; the Clarksville, TN chapter is making an impack in their community by donating masks to teachers, providing
      meals to those in need during Thanksgiving and Christmas and other activies supporting youth and highway cleanup projects.
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      In the &lt;b&gt;Western Frontier&lt;/b&gt; the South Bay, CA chapter has a philosophy of charitable giving as a regular practice.  As they describe on their web site
      "South Bay Soldiers always ride with homeless care bags on their bikes. We give them out 365 days a year during our rides."
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      All are correct
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is f. &lt;br&gt;All are examples of chapters giving back to their communities.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
  <questionDetail topic="Accomplishments">
    <question>
      While the mission of the Buffalo Soldiers includes a range of goals including educating, preserving history, community involvement, scholarships, providing postivie role models and much more, this is still a motorcycle club.
      Riding is a fundamental to the group's existance.  Which is true about why we ride.
    </question>
    <answer correct="false">
      To show the colors and represent the Buffalo Soldiers publically
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Establish bonds with our fellow riding brothers and sisters
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      Fellowship with other bikers that we meet along the way
    </answer>
    <answer correct="false">
      It's our passion
    </answer>
    <answer correct="true">
      All of the above
    </answer>
    <explanation>
      The correct answer is e.
    </explanation>
  </questionDetail>
  //--------------------------------------------------------
</buffaloSoldiers>
